hey everyone welcome back again
so today uh we are going to continue
from where we left in our last session
where we are talking about how we can
execute or steer our Tosca Commander
using uh the command line tool which is
known as the TC shell we have also seen
how we can even execute a particular
execution list right from the command
prompt using this DC shell right without
opening the Tosca Commander now we are
going one step further
so here we still have a manual process
like we are opening command prompt and
we are entering some commands here uh to
do some execution but what if we want to
automate this whole process we don't
want to open command prompt or don't
want to enter in commands we just want
to click
um on a particular link or button and it
should just execute right or even
schedule our events at a certain time at
a certain day or depending on some other
conditions right so all of this is
possible uh obviously with uh continuous
integration tool like Jenkins so today
we are going to see how you can perform
all of these tasks in Jenkins right
before I jump uh into Jenkins uh we will
need a batch file Windows batch file in
order to execute our
script.tcs right so the script.tcs
contains uh the commands which we want
to execute
but uh to execute this particular script
uh we would require a batch file which
can call this particular script right
because we cannot execute this script
file directly in Jenkins
so I have created a execute.bat file and
if I edit this particular file you will
see that it contains the same commands
which we have seen earlier okay
so the First Command will open the
commander home folder and then the TC
cell command which will basically call
the dot TCS file right so those are the
two commands which are present in this
patch file you can always
create a batch file using a notepad just
type the commands and then dot then just
save it as a DOT bat file okay
so let's go into our Jenkins now I have
already logged it into my Jenkins local
instance right if you are using a server
instance the steps will still remain
same there might be some minor changes
or you have to maybe configure a little
bit more but still you can follow the
same process okay
so for this uh I will create a new
project here I will choose freestyle
project I can also choose a pipeline
right
so let's give it a proper name here I
will say Tosca execute underscore CI
okay and click on OK
now there are a lot of configuration
which is present in Jenkins which you
can configure for your project right you
can give it a description you can do all
this discard old builds right uh you can
integrate it with the source code
management tool like get
you can schedule your bills using the
build triggers uh either periodically or
with get the same polling or pole SCM
right
so if you want to look at how to
configure all of this in Jenkins you can
go to my Jenkins playlist you will find
all different videos present on these
different options okay we don't require
to configure all of this since we are
running it on a local Jenkins instance I
just need the build step okay so here I
will do add build step and then I will
say execute Windows patch command since
I'm working on a Windows machine
um and here I need to pass some commands
so that I'm able to run that Windows
batch file okay so for that it's pretty
simple uh I just need to change the
directory first to this particular uh
directory and then I need to call
execute dot bat
which is the name of my batch file okay
and then I just need to save it
once I save it just make sure that Tosca
Commander is not open with the workspace
okay if it's normally open that's fine
but if you have logged into the
workspace then just make sure you have
closed the workspace otherwise you will
get uh some funny issues in Jenkins okay
so after this uh just click on Bell now
and the bill will start so we can even
look at the console output here
so the output in the console would still
be very similar to what we have seen
earlier uh in while executing it from
the command prompt right so it will
basically log into the workspace it will
start the tasks what we have provided in
that script file so no matter what you
want to do you can just make your script
file and then just run this patch file
so it will just perform all the tasks
which is present in that script file
okay so as you can see the build is
successful
and that's how easy is to integrate
Jenkins with your Tosca Commander right
you can directly run your test cases or
perform some other tasks write on your
Tosca Commander using Jenkins you can
even schedule your bills as I said
earlier right
so that's all about how you can run or
steer your Tasker Commander using the
command line tool which is TC shell and
you can do it directly from Jenkins you
just have to create a batch file which
will be referring to the uh TCS script
file and which will in turn perform all
the different actions or tasks which
um are there for the Tosca Commander
right
so uh if you have any questions just put
them in the comments and I will
certainly try to get back to you uh do
look out for more videos uh which are
coming up uh in Tosca there are lots of
different topics which I want to cover
so keep looking out for those videos in
the coming updates